Summary

Software engineer with around 8 years of experience building clean and maintainable software for a wide range of businesses ranging from Augmented Reality to Financial Services. Possess a strong technical background with a Masters Degree in Computer Engineering from the University of Florida. Lots of experience working in agile teams and also some independently as the only developer. Currently looking for a challenging new role in AWS Serverless development and some fun people to work with. I have been living in the Netherlands for more than 5 years now and can speak Dutch as well:)

Recent Work Experience

Moneyou / ABN AMRO (Financial Services)

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

March 2018 - December 2018

Senior Developer - Freelance

- Part of team doing iOS feature development and releases
- Interview new Candidates
- Won moneyou hackathon and successfully implemented suggested features in the app
- Part of team creating a new and compliant banking infrastructure with AWS Serverless Lambdas

Markplaats / Ebay Inc. (Classifieds)

 ${\bf Amsterdam},\,{\bf The}\,\,{\bf Netherlands}$

Senior Developer - Freelance

June 2016 - December 2017

- Singlehandedly maintain the 2dehands.be App for Belgium serving millions of users
- Part of the ebay global mobile team building classified apps for 11 different countries for example Gumtree UK
- Setup all required processes such as Automated Testing, Continuous Integration, Crash Analysis etc.
- Won markplaats hackathon twice consecutively
- Successfully hired and trained replacement for the role before exit

Layar / Blippar (Augmented Reality)

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Senior Developer - Permanent

November 2014 - May 2016

- Lead Developer for the Layar App that makes millions of users see Augmented Reality
- Lead Developer for the Layar SDK that help businesses make Augmented Reality solutions
- Part of the team building the Blippar App for visual search

Previous Work Experience

IceMobile Agency

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Senior Developer

February 2014 - November 2014

- Senior developer in the development team building apps for the leading supermarkets in the Netherlands such as Jumbo and Albert Heijn
- Gathering business requirements and coming up with efficient technical solutions to address them
- Automating user interface testing and setting up continuous integration

Ebuddy

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Medior Developer

June 2013 - January 2014

- Working in the development team building the messaging app XMS that had millions of users around the world and was a competitor to watsapp

Simple Apps LLC

Owner

New Delhi, India February 2012 - June 2013

- Started an App development company and built several apps under it

MicroStrategy Inc.

McLean,VA

Software Engineer

September 2010 - January 2012

- Worked on several iOS development projects for the clients of Microstrategy and helped automate various tasks. Also helped develop the microstrategy SDK. iOS was a pretty new technology at this point so this was some really good experience.

Citisync.com

Gainesville,FL

 $iOS\ Developer$

January 2010- July 2010

- Singlehandedly built the citisync iOS Application. This was when iOS 3 was the latest version. Also my first experience as an iOS Developer and it piqued my interest in the field

Bloomberg LP

New York, NY

Software Engineering Intern

May 2009 - August 2009

- As an intern in the manhattan office, I helped out with a number of projects in the Global Trading team writing code in C++ and managing large mainframe supercomputers

Education

University of Florida

Gaineville,FL

Masters in Computer Engineering

August 2008 - August 2010

- CGPA: 3.6/4.0

Skills

Languages: Javascript (Node), Swift, Objective C, C, C++, Python, Bash

Technical Skills: Test Driven Development, Automated UI Testing, Continuous Integration, fastlane, git, xcode, Security, Machine learning with Deep Neural Nets, Restful API Design, AWS Serverless Development

Business Skills: Agile/Scrum, Managing Expectations, Project Estimation, Converting Business Goals to Technical Requirements, Risk Management, Presentations and Demos

Other Interests

Pilot Training, Salsa Dancing, Spanish, Hiking, Travel, Poker, Pool and Snooker